An Ashburn neighborhood is suddenly
finding itself in the headlines after
word got out homeowners there were being
offered $4 million
each to sell for data center
development.
>> But some residents say that headline
doesn't at all represent an accurate
picture of the quandary they face.
>> Yeah, northern Virginia bureau chief
Julie Carey visited the Regency HOA to
try to get more details behind this
catchy headline.
The Regency neighborhood just off
Waxpool Road in Ashburn is beautiful
this time of year. 143 spacious
half-acre lots, open space, just blocks
to the metro and shopping. But here's
the problem. On two sides, the
subdivision is surrounded by data
centers and more are coming. There's
noise and they can be an eyesore. That
led the former HOA president Mittal
Gandhi, a real estate developer, to
devise a plan. He found a data center
developer who would pay each homeowner
roughly $4 million
to buy them out. Kept mostly quiet for
more than a year, the proposal was just
spotlighted in a data center
publication, then in the local paper.
In a statement to News4, Gandhi writes
in part, "Our goal is to explore whether
a true win-win-win solution existed for
our community, our county, and a
responsible developer. Even when those
opportunities arise, bringing 143
homeowners together is incredibly
challenging given the human element
involved." He says he's continuing to
see if all residents are willing to be
on board. We spoke to at least a dozen
residents about the proposal, but not
one, including Gandhi, would agree to be
interviewed on camera. Some telling me
the proposal has created friction in the
neighborhood. Others saying the original
proposal will not move forward because
not enough residents could agree to its
terms. The HOA president issuing a
statement reading in part, "There is
currently no offer to purchase the
Regency homes for data center
development." One big hurdle to any sort
of redevelopment here, this is currently
zoned residential. And that means any
application to permit a data center here
would require every single homeowner to
also sign on to that application.
Supervisor Sylvia Glass represents this
area. Her office says she is aware
Regency has received outreach from data
center developers and she's spoken to
residents. But she adds in a written
statement, "I am not involved in any
negotiations the community may be having
and no rezoning application has been
submitted to Loudoun County." While
development opportunities might exist
for an area so close to the Ashburn
metro station, the county's
comprehensive plan calls for housing,
commercial, and civic uses on that land.
Still, even some residents who tell me
they've rejected the original proposal
say they are open to other options. They
say the quality of life in the dream
home they bought here 20 or 30 years ago
is no longer the same with more data
centers looming on their horizon. In
Ashburn, Virginia, I'm Julie Carey,
News4.
Okay, so we want to know how much it
would it take for you to sell your
property to data center developers?
>> Yeah, twice, triple, or quadruple your
home value, or would you refuse to sell?
You can chime in by scanning that QR
code on your screen there. You can also
head to our website, that's
nbcwashington.com.
I don't know.
>> Can't buy me 85%
>> me out. Wow. I would For $4 million, I
would do it in a heartbeat. I would take
the money and run.
>> times the amount is only 2%. I don't
know. I I'd take it. Four times? Wow.
>> I'm sorry, I would take the money and
run.
All right.